Test, test.
测试  测试
Can people hear me?
大家能听到我说话吗？
You can hear on Zoom?
Zoom 上能听到吗？
Excellent.
太好了
All right, all right.
好的  好的
That should be good.
这样应该就可以了
Should this be pinned or something?
这个应该固定住吗？
Mind if I get the mic first?
介意我先用麦克风吗？
You mind?
你介意吗？
Let's put up the current calendar.
让我们看一下目前的日程安排
Kind of like going over a brief overview of what's going on in the class.
就像简要概述一下课程内容
How's everyone doing?
大家都好吗？
Good.
很好
There's so few people today.
今天人这么少
Is it?
是吗？
It's optional.
这是可选的
It's Friday.
今天是星期五
That too.
那也是
Huh?
Oh, it's a nice out.
哦  天气真好
There's something special going on tomorrow too, right?
明天好像也有什么特别的活动  对吧？
Supposedly?
好像是这样？
I've heard it's a holiday.
我听说是个节日
Anyway, yeah, so from now on, all the lectures are going to be optional.
总之  从现在开始  所有的课程都是可选的了
We kind of want you to focus on your Project 3 if you need to.
如果需要的话  我们希望你们能专注于 Project 3
Nevertheless, we're going to have a lot of cool topics that we go over over the next few days.
尽管如此  在接下来的几天里  我们还会讲很多很酷的主题
So please show up if you can.
如果可以的话  请尽量来上课
If you're watching on the recording, because there's not many people here today, then please show up for the remaining lectures.
如果你是在看录像  因为今天来的人不多  那么请尽量来参加剩下的课程
They're going to be fun.
这些课会很有趣的
In any case, other than that, yeah, I think only project 3B is next, right?
总之  除此之外  我想接下来就只有 Project 3B 了  对吧？
And that's due on Monday.
截止日期是周一
After that, yeah, after that it's single homework and it's the final.
之后  就只剩下一份作业和期末考试了
All right, so today is going to be our final software engineering lecture.
好的  今天是我们的最后一节软件工程课
So we'll be covering over video game design.
我们将讨论电子游戏设计
And here to perform our lecture here is Circle, one of our TAs, and I think one of the head TAs for over the summer, maybe?
今天来给我们讲课的是 Circle  他是我们的一位助教  我想他可能是暑期班的首席助教？
I don't know.
我不知道
Maybe.
也许吧
We don't know.
我们也不知道
We're still trying to figure that out.
我们还在确认中
Anyway, let's give it up for Circle.
不管怎样  让我们欢迎 Circle！
Ready to hold the mic when I'm talking?
我说话的时候  你能帮我拿一下麦克风吗？
Yeah, and then hang on.
好的  然后等一下
Should I clip this?
我应该夹住它吗？
Okay.
Do I need to clip this or should I hold it?
我需要夹住它  还是拿着它？
Okay.
Because I feel like it might be better if I clip it.
因为我觉得夹住它可能会更好
Because I'm not going to be doing stuff with my hands.
因为我不会用手做什么事情
Okay.
Actually, let me just do this.
实际上  让我来做吧
Hi. Let me start sharing.
嗨   让我开始分享
I think it's not sharing.
我觉得它没有分享
So I'm going to start sharing my screen.
我将开始分享我的屏幕
Oh, it is.
哦  它正在分享
OK, that's good.
好的  那很好
Yeah.
Hello. Hope everyone's doing well.
大家好   希望大家都过得很好
OK.
Let's see.
我们来看看
Let me just turn that off.
让我把这个关掉
Alright, so I'm Circle Chen, I'm from China, and this is my sixth time TAing for this course.
好的  我是Circle  来自中国  这是我第六次担任这门课程的助教
And I love all things game-related.
我喜欢所有与游戏相关的东西
I also play game music at the Intermission Orchestra.
我还在 Intermission Orchestra 乐团演奏游戏音乐
I have my itch profile, these are some of my games I made.
这是我的 itch 个人资料  上面展示了我制作的一些游戏
So today we're going to cover game development.
今天我们将讨论游戏开发
And specifically indie game development.
特别是独立游戏开发
If we think about what we did in the introductory CS courses, these actually all involve some sort of game building.
如果我们回顾一下我们在 CS 入门课程中所做的内容  这些实际上都涉及某种游戏构建
In 61A, you did the game Hog.
在 61A 中  你们做了 Hog 游戏
It's like a game of dice.
这就像一个骰子游戏
We did Ants. It's like a Planet vs. Zombie copy.
我们做了 Ants 游戏   它就像一个植物大战僵尸的副本
In 61B, we built these two games, 2048 and Build Your Own World.
在 61B 中  我们构建了这两个游戏：2048 和 Build Your Own World(BYOW)
Now, you might wonder, why do we do games?
现在  你可能会想  为什么我们要做游戏呢？
Why is game development always so crucial?
为什么游戏开发总是如此重要？
We do these because games are fun, and we hope that the pleasure of implementing a game is actually going to be a motivation for you to learn programming further.
我们这样做是因为游戏很有趣  我们希望实现游戏的乐趣能够真正激励你进一步学习编程
So that's why we give you assignments that are on games.
这就是为什么我们给你们的作业都是关于游戏的
Now, let's say some of you, after you're finished with all the game building, think about, okay, what if I want to take a step forward and make this a hobby?
现在  假设你们中的一些人  在完成了所有的游戏构建之后  想更进一步  把它作为一种爱好  会怎么样呢？
Some of you then, indie game development might be a good fit for you.
那么对于你们中的一些人来说  独立游戏开发可能是一个不错的选择
This is what I'm going to discuss.
我要讨论的就是这个
The word indie here means independent.
这里的“独立”是指独立开发者
This will be contrast as if you're working with game companies like Blizzard or Riot.
这与在暴雪或拳头游戏公司工作形成对比
There's a lot more freedom you can do, but it can still be very demanding because you need to set your own deadlines and manage your own work schedule.
你可以做的事情自由度更高  但仍然很有挑战性  因为你需要设定自己的截止日期和管理自己的工作时间表
Now, we have these slide color background.
现在  我们有这些幻灯片颜色背景
We have those blue slides, and those might be useful for Build Your Own World.
我们有那些蓝色幻灯片  它们可能对“构建你自己的世界”有用
And we have these white slides, and these will be important for future game development.
我们还有这些白色幻灯片  这些对未来的游戏开发很重要
I'm going to close that. Is it possible to close the black windows there?
我要关掉它   可以把那边的黑色窗口关掉吗？
Okay.
Let's just see.
让我们看看
Okay.
Oh.
OK, let's see.
好的  让我们看看
Does the audio still work on Zoom or something?
Zoom的音频还能用吗？
Can people still hear me in the back?
后面的人还能听到我说话吗？
OK, I'll probably just hold the mic because, yeah, it's a little bit tiring.
好的  我可能就直接拿着麦克风了  是的  有点累
In Project 3A, Phase A and B, you created random worlds and you enabled the player to move around the world using keyboards.
在项目3A的A阶段和B阶段  你创建了随机世界  并使玩家能够使用键盘在世界中移动
Phase C involves adding new features to make it an actual game.
C阶段包括添加新功能  使其成为一个真正的游戏
The key question is, how do you design a good game?
关键问题是  如何设计一个好的游戏？
The key concept and the key rationale for making a game good is that you should engage the player, or if you engage them too much, then you can say the game is a little bit addictive.
制作好游戏  关键的概念和基本原理是让玩家投入其中  如果玩家过于投入  你甚至可以说这款游戏有点让人上瘾
One example here is Flappy Bird.
举个例子  比如Flappy Bird
How many of you have no Flappy Bird played it before?
在座有多少人没玩过Flappy Bird？
Yeah, that's a lot of people.
看来玩过的人很多
In Flappy Bird, the player's action space is very limited.
在Flappy Bird中  玩家的操作空间非常有限
There's just one action, which is to tap the screen.
只有一个操作  就是点击屏幕
When you tap the screen, the bird just flies up a little bit and then it falls down due to gravity.
当你点击屏幕时  小鸟只会向上飞一点  然后就会因为重力而掉下来
The tricky thing about Flappy Bird is that it's really difficult to time the clicks correctly, and you want to avoid all these pipes and stuff.
Flappy Bird的难点在于  很难掌握点击的时机  而且你要避开所有这些管道之类的东西
One takeaway from Flappy Bird is that you want your game mechanics to be very easy to learn.
Flappy Bird给我们的一点启示是  你的游戏机制要易于学习
For example, a very simple and not complex action space.
例如  一个非常简单而不复杂的操作空间
But there should be something interesting in your game that makes your actions really hard to master.
但是你的游戏中应该有一些有趣的东西  让你的操作很难精通
Now, you might have this question.
现在  你可能会问这个问题
Flappy Bird is a very simple game, only one action space.
Flappy Bird是一个非常简单的游戏  只有一个操作空间
What if my game mechanisms are inherently complicated?
如果我的游戏机制本身就很复杂呢？
It isn't very interesting if I just want a player to be able to do one thing.
如果我只想让玩家能够做一件事  那就没什么意思了
They should be able to do four things, ten things.
他们应该能够做四件事  十件事
You want a way to make the player learn the mechanisms gradually.
你需要一种方法让玩家逐渐学习这些机制
That's why most of you might have seen in some games that we have tutorial levels, which are explicit textual instructions given by the game.
这就是为什么你们大多数人可能在一些游戏中看到过教程关卡  也就是游戏给出的明确的文字说明
They might be embedded in an actual level, so you might still have a task, but the game still tells you what to do.
这些说明可能嵌入在一个实际的关卡中  所以你可能仍然有一个任务  但是游戏仍然会告诉你该做什么
The game will still tell you, you should activate this switch, or you should open this door or something.
游戏仍然会告诉你  你应该启动这个开关  或者你应该打开这扇门什么的
Here is a tutorial from Genshin Impact.
这是来自原神的一个教程
As you can see, there are actually levels that let you trigger some sort of an elemental reaction, but the game is telling you, okay, when Pyro meets Dendro, it triggers burning,
可以看到有一些关卡可以让你触发某种元素反应  但游戏会告诉你  当火遇到草时  它会触发燃烧
and then basically it's kind of like reading a textbook or something, just like a miniature version.
然后基本上就像读教科书或什么的  就像一个微型版本
There's one issue with tutorial levels, although they're systematic.
教程关卡虽然系统化  但有一个问题
Players don't learn by reading text.
玩家不是通过阅读文本来学习的
They learn by interacting with the world.
他们通过与世界互动来学习
This is one thing you might have heard of when you're doing your application essay for colleges or something, which is show, don't tell.
当你写大学申请论文或其他东西时  你可能听说过一句话  那就是“展示  不要说”
That's why we introduced the concept called an anti-peace.
这就是为什么我们引入了“反和平”的概念
Anti-peace basically means that you have an innocuous task that precedes a very big challenge.
反和平基本上意味着你有一个无害的任务  然后是一个非常大的挑战
This task is going to hint you at how you could resolve that challenge.
这个任务会暗示你如何解决这个挑战
So let's take a look at the word hint there.
让我们来看看“暗示”这个词
The word hint doesn't actually mean the game tells you what to do, but you should figure it out.
暗示这个词并不意味着游戏告诉你该做什么  但你应该自己弄清楚
So there are no explicit verbal instructions, and the player should just figure things out.
所以没有明确的口头指示  玩家应该自己弄清楚
There's another example, Portal 2.
还有一个例子  传送门2
So this lecture is going to have a lot of concrete examples from various games, because each game just has different elements.
这节课将会有很多来自不同游戏的具体例子  因为每个游戏都有不同的元素
I'll try to introduce the context for people who never play the game.
我会尽量向从未玩过游戏的人介绍背景
In Portal 2, the player can place two connecting portals to transport themselves.
在传送门2中  玩家可以放置两个连接的门户来传送自己
They need to use these portals to overcome obstacles.
他们需要使用这些门户来克服障碍
Here is one example level from Portal 2.
这是来自传送门2的一个关卡示例
You actually have these platforms that are an obstacle.
你实际上有这些平台作为障碍
You want to go up here.
你想上去这里
The height is designed so that the player cannot just jump on the platform.
这个高度设计成玩家不能直接跳到平台上
But then you will see that there is an orange portal already created for you.
但你会发现那里已经为你创建了一个橙色传送门
If you place a blue portal on the wall, actually anywhere, you can even place it on the floor,
如果你在墙上放置一个蓝色传送门  实际上可以在任何地方
and you enter that portal, you're actually going to come out of the orange portal.
你甚至可以把它放在地板上  然后你进入那个传送门  你实际上会从橙色传送门出来
This will actually have the height, and then you're likely going to have some velocity that puts you in a projectile motion, and that takes you on this platform.
这实际上会有一定高度  然后你可能会有一些速度  使你进入抛物线运动  然后把你带到这个平台上
The key idea here is that this introduces a forward movement out of a portal across a gap to a place you couldn't reach.
这里的关键思想是  这引入了从传送门向前移动  跨过一个缺口  到达你无法到达的地方
This is some sort of a heuristic when you're playing the game.
当你玩游戏时  这是一种启发式方法
If you notice this panel here, this is a protruding thrust-forward panel with an orange portal on it.
如果你注意到这里的这个面板  这是一个突出的向前推力的面板  上面有一个橙色传送门
Whenever you see something like this, you're going to think back to this level and what you did.
每当你看到这样的东西  你都会想起这一关和你所做的事情
Now comes the real challenge.
现在真正的挑战来了
Here's a room with a larger gap and a deep hole.
这是一个房间  有一个更大的缺口和一个很深的洞
Now, this black platform here is quite narrow, and the player is likely to fall in the pit.
现在  这里的黑色平台相当窄  玩家很可能会掉进坑里
They cannot go out unless they create a floor portal,
他们不能出去  除非他们创建一个地板传送门
because the game's rule is that these black surfaces, you cannot really create portals on them.
因为游戏的规则是  这些黑色表面  你不能真正地在其上创建传送门
You have to create them on the floor.
你必须在地板上创建它们
This actually sets them up for the solution.
这实际上为他们设置了解决方案
If they just jump in through that portal, they're going to come out of the orange portal.
如果他们只是跳进那个传送门  他们会从橙色传送门出来
This actually brings them back to where they started.
这实际上让他们回到了起点
If they look at this more closely, they'll actually realize something similar to the previous level.
如果他们更仔细地观察  他们实际上会意识到与上一关类似的东西
We have this portal.
我们有这个传送门
If they recall what they did in the previous level, if you fall into another portal,
如果他们回忆起他们在上一关所做的事情  如果你掉进另一个传送门
that will actually give you enough velocity to come out of this, and then that should thrust you out from here.
那实际上会给你足够的速度从这里出来  然后那应该把你从这里推出
Now, if you jump into that blue portal intentionally, this is actually going to make you thrust it to the other side.
现在  如果你故意跳进那个蓝色传送门  这实际上会让你把它推到另一边
So you go here, and then you're on the other side.
这边走  然后就到另一边了
Yeah, so that's Entei Piece.
对  这就是Entei Piece
You've seen that Entei Piece is how players learn, but why would the player want to learn?
我们已经了解了Entei Piece是玩家学习的方式  但为什么玩家想要学习呢？
The key issue is that most people play games because they want to relax.
关键问题是大多数人玩游戏是为了放松
They don't want to learn.
他们不想学习
They don't want to do another 61b stuff or gaming.
他们不想再做61B之类的东西或游戏
We want motivation.
我们需要动力
The player needs to be motivated to learn game mechanics, and that's when feedback comes in.
玩家需要有动力去学习游戏机制  这就是反馈的作用
It'll be somewhat similar to what you see in psychology.
这和你在心理学中看到的内容有些类似
You have reinforcement and punishment.
你有强化和惩罚
It's like the behaviorism thing that you did to the rats to make them do some sort of behavior, like electric shocks or food or something.
就像你对老鼠做行为主义实验一样  用电击或食物之类的东西让它们做出某种行为
Now, the first concept here is positive feedback.
现在  第一个概念是正反馈
It's more like a reward, and basically, when you have positive feedback, the player does well,
它更像是一种奖励  基本上  当你有正反馈时  玩家表现出色
and then they'll gain items, abilities, such that it'll make their game become easier.
他们就会获得物品、能力  从而使他们的游戏变得更容易
Now, the opposite is also true.
反之亦然
If they don't do well, they just don't get those items, so the game is kind of harder.
如果他们做得不好  他们就得不到那些物品  所以游戏就会变得更难
Now, if the game becomes easier, they're more likely to do well, and this becomes like a self-reinforcing cycle.
现在  如果游戏变得更容易  他们就更有可能做得更好  这就变成了一个自我强化的循环
So, some examples, in most of the multiplayer combat games, the more opponents a player defeats,
举个例子  在大多数多人战斗游戏中  玩家击败的对手越多  他们获得的资源就越多
the more resources they're going to get, and they can purchase more items, which enables them to defeat even more opponents.
他们可以购买更多的物品  这使得他们能够击败更多的对手
So, some example games, League of Legends, maybe.
一些例子游戏  比如英雄联盟
Now, here's a question for the audience.
现在  给观众们一个问题
What are some problems if positive feedback is too strong in a game?
如果正反馈在游戏中太强  会有什么问题？
Think about it for maybe a couple of seconds.
思考几秒钟
Okay.
Yeah, I'm just going to roll back to like the... So we were having these.
嗯  我想要回到……之前我们讨论的那些
So yeah, any answers here?
那么  这里有什么答案吗？
What are some problems if positive feedback is too strong?
如果正反馈太强  会有什么问题？
Yeah, they're in the back.
是的  他们在后面
Yeah, so the game gets too easy and boring.
所以游戏会变得太容易和无聊
That's exactly right.
完全正确
You know, if you're at the position where, like, you just don't have to do anything, and then you just win the game.
你知道  如果你处于那种什么都不用做就能赢得游戏的位置
And the opposite is also kind of true, you know.
反之亦然  你知道的
If you made some small mistakes in the beginning, what's gonna happen?
如果你在一开始犯了一些小错误  会发生什么？
The game just becomes too hard, right?
游戏就变得太难了  对吧？
Because there's, like, the opposite becomes even greater.
因为相反的情况变得更严重了
So, just as you said,
所以  正如你所说
If positive feedback is too strong in the game, players who are behind are very hard to catch up, and there's a lot of focus on early game decisions, and the leading players just lead.
如果游戏中的正反馈太强  落后的玩家很难追赶  而且游戏会过度关注前期决策  领先的玩家会一直领先
There's no interesting things to the game.
游戏中就没有有趣的事情了
So we have a contrary aspect called negative feedback.
所以我们有一个相反的概念  叫做负反馈
When the player does well, the game actually becomes harder by giving them more challenging levels or worse items.
当玩家表现出色时  游戏实际上会通过给他们更具挑战性的关卡或更差的道具来变得更难
You know, things are just more interesting if you have a lot of people in the middle, especially like if you're playing Mario Kart where you're having fun with your games.
你知道  如果有很多玩家在中间  事情就会更有趣  尤其是当你玩马里奥赛车时  你会玩得很开心
It wouldn't be really fun if like just one player is ahead of the game and then the rest of the players are just like, you know, just doing their thing or falling behind.
如果只有一个玩家领先  而其他玩家只是在做自己的事情或落后  那就没什么意思了
Yeah, the racing game example.
是的  就是那个赛车游戏的例子
If you're the last place player, you actually have a higher chance to get boosting items or you have like some weapons to knock out the leading players.
如果你是最后一名  实际上你更有可能获得加速道具  或者你有一些武器可以击倒领先的玩家
Now, let's think about the mirror question here.
现在  让我们思考一下关于这个问题的反面
What are some problems when negative feedback is too strong in a game?
当负反馈在游戏中过强时  会有什么问题？
Yeah?
是吗？
Sorry, can you repeat that?
抱歉  你能重复一遍吗？
So that's a great thought.
这是一个很好的想法
So you said it's going to become too hard.
你说游戏会变得太难了
So what I'm going to point out here is that when the player actually doesn't do that well, the game is actually trying to help them by making the game length easier.
我要指出的是  当玩家表现不佳时  游戏实际上试图通过降低游戏难度来帮助他们
So I wouldn't say it's necessarily becoming too hard.
我不会说它一定会变得太难
Yeah.
Yeah, exactly.
是的  没错
So there's no motivation for you to get better, because even if you just don't do well, you can just rely on the game giving you good stuff.
你就没有动力去提高自己  因为即使你表现不好  你也可以依靠游戏给你好东西
I think some people will just complain to me when they play League of Legends.
我想有些人玩英雄联盟的时候会向我抱怨
When they win, the game tends to give them worse teammates, so they lose.
当他们赢的时候  游戏往往会给他们更差的队友  所以他们输了
And then if they lose, the game just gives them better teammates.
如果他们输了  游戏就会给他们更好的队友
So their win rate just stays at 50%, no matter what the skills are.
所以他们的胜率始终保持在50%  无论他们的技术如何
So if the player sees that, well, they're just not going to hone their skills.
如果玩家看到这一点  他们就不会磨练自己的技术了
Now, one thing you might notice is that these type of negative feedbacks are actually better suited for party games, where people shouldn't be judged on their skill or something.
你可能会注意到  这类负反馈实际上更适合聚会游戏  在这些游戏中  人们不应该以他们的技术或其他东西来评判
They just want to have fun together.
他们只是想一起玩得开心
So you might see Mario Kart have more of them.
你可能会看到像马里奥赛车这样的游戏更多一些
Whereas positive feedback is more like competitive games, maybe like Starcraft.
而正反馈更像是竞技游戏  比如星际争霸
And speaking of motivation, there's actually another problem.
说到动机  其实还有另一个问题
The player knows everything after a successful run, so the game just becomes very boring because you know all the tricks.
玩家在一次成功通关后就知道了所有的事情  所以游戏变得非常无聊  因为你已经知道了所有的技巧
So you need a variability of game experience.
所以你需要游戏体验的多样性
There are a lot of ways you can do this.
有很多方法可以做到这一点
You can randomize each run by randomizing items, rooms, or you could just keep on adding new content.
你可以通过随机分配物品、房间来随机分配每次运行  或者你可以不断添加新内容
I put some examples of games who tries to do that.
我举了一些尝试这样做的游戏的例子
This is a game where the rooms are randomly placed.
这是一个房间随机放置的游戏
This is just one possible configuration.
这只是一个可能的配置
The boss is here.
老板在这里
It could be somewhere else.
它可能在别的地方
This game is called Binding of Isaac.
这个游戏叫做以撒的结合
And here, this is Genshin Impact 4.6.
在这里  这是原神4.6版本
I have a new character, Arlecchino, added in.
我有一个新角色  仆人  加入了进来
So these are two ways you can make the player still engaged.
所以这是两种可以让玩家保持参与的方法
Yeah. Let's see, I'll do it on time.
是的   让我们看看  我会准时完成的
So what elements would you add to Build Your Own World to make it a good game?
那么你会在“构建你自己的世界”中添加哪些元素来让它成为一个好游戏呢？
So this is a time for people to discuss with your neighbors, think about it for like a few minutes,
所以现在是人们与你的邻居讨论的时间  思考几分钟
and then let's try to share what people will try to come up because this is actually part of like project 3C.
然后让我们尝试分享人们会尝试想出什么  因为这实际上是项目3C的一部分
Okay, don't worry.
好的  别担心
This is just a talk.
这只是一个演讲
I don't think there's any skin chat.
我觉得应该不会有什么皮肤聊天
Okay, cool.
好的  没问题
Okay, yeah.
是的
I'm gonna try to... Hide floating control panels.
我试试... 隐藏浮动控制面板
Let's see.
让我们看看
OK, that's full screen.
好的  这就是全屏了
Yeah, I guess I could just ask people to share.
是的  我想我可以让人们分享一下
Actually, there's someone in the chat.
实际上  聊天室里有人
Okay, that's good.
好的  那很好
I'm going to stop sharing now.
我现在要停止分享了
Yeah, Justin will be typing some of the responses that people write, so you can all see.
好的  贾斯汀会输入一些人们写的回复  这样你们都能看到
Does anyone want to share what they have?
有人想分享他们所拥有的吗？
I'll also be checking the Zoom chat if people have any ideas.
我还会查看Zoom聊天室  看看人们是否有什么想法
Yeah, in the back.
好的  在后面
You could add an emergent concept to create a storyline.
你可以添加一个涌现的概念来创建一个故事情节
Okay, so the concept of an emergent storyline.
好的  那么涌现的故事情节的概念
Is that what you're suggesting?
这就是你的建议吗？
Yeah, that could be interesting.
是的  那可能会很有趣
You add some sort of a lore.
添加一些背景故事
Do we have anyone else?
还有其他人想补充吗？
Yeah?
有吗？
Yeah, enemies, obstacles, player needs to overcome.
对  敌人  障碍  玩家需要克服的东西
There.
那里
Oh sorry, what system?
哦  抱歉  什么系统？
Point system.
积分系统
Can you elaborate a little bit more on how you would try to use that?
你能详细说明一下你想如何使用它吗？
Oh yeah.
哦  好的
Yeah, exactly.
没错
So point system like you have like a score running thing.
所以积分系统就像一个运行的计分器
Good idea.
好主意
Okay, we'll try to do like maybe one or two more.
好的  我们再尝试一两个吧
People have any?
还有人想补充吗？
Yeah.
有
Yeah, so you know points just currency or money where you can purchase stuff.
积分就像货币  可以用来购买东西
That could be interesting.
那可能很有趣
All right, let's see.
好吧  我们看看
Do we still have any others?
还有其他人想补充吗？
OK, I think this is a good place to stop.
好的  我想可以结束了
These ones are really good ideas.
这些想法确实不错
They're definitely somewhat different from the last time I did this lecture.
它们和我上次讲课时讲的肯定有些不同
So it's really interesting to see people contribute to this discussion.
所以看到人们参与讨论真的很有意思
So we're now going to move on.
那么我们现在继续
Let's see.
让我们看看
Let's do this.
我们开始吧
So we're going to discuss the pipelines of making a game.
所以我们将讨论制作游戏的流程
And let's say you designed those game mechanics like the ones you mentioned above.
假设你设计了像上面提到的那些游戏机制
How would you actually turn it into a final product?
你将如何把它变成最终产品？
Now, you'll need to work with a lot of different people on your team.
现在  你需要和团队中的许多不同的人一起工作
You're going to be working with designers, artists, or musicians.
你将与设计师、艺术家或音乐家合作
And you're going to be working with other programmers.
你将与其他程序员合作
And you're going to be working with testers.
你将与测试人员合作
And there's also a timeline for starting from a game and making it an actual thing.
从游戏开始到把它变成一个实际的东西  还有一个时间表
So you're going to start with an idea, and then you're going to create paper prototypes, and then you create a minimum viable product, abbreviated as MVP.
所以你将从一个想法开始  然后创建纸质原型  然后创建一个最小可行产品  缩写为MVP
And then you iteratively improve your game by going through alpha, beta, and release.
然后  你通过经历α、β和发布来迭代地改进你的游戏
So I'll just explain using Minecraft as an example, but the general process should be the same no matter what game you're looking into.
所以我将以《我的世界》为例进行解释  但无论你看的是什么游戏  一般的过程都应该是一样的
So the ideation phase is a couple sentences or elements relevant to the game.
因此  构思阶段是与游戏相关的几句话或元素
And for Minecraft, this includes some of these rationales.
对于《我的世界》来说  这包括以下一些原理
So for Build Your Own World, it's actually kind of similar.
所以对于“建造你自己的世界”来说  它实际上有点类似
The idea is like randomly generate a world with rooms and hallways, and you have an avatar that can move.
这个想法就像是随机生成一个包含房间和走廊的世界  然后你有一个可以移动的角色
Now, this is one of the games Minecraft is inspired by.
这是《我的世界》灵感来源的游戏之一
It's called Infant Miner.
它叫做《矮人矿工》
You have block-based worlds.
它拥有方块构成的世界
Now we then have a paper prototype.
然后我们会有一个纸上原型
So basically, this just presents the game on paper.
基本上  这只是将游戏呈现在纸上
And then the purpose of this is just for people to discuss all the ideas, and they can make changes quickly without actually writing any code.
这样做的目的是让人们可以讨论所有的想法  并且可以快速地进行更改  而无需实际编写任何代码
Because when you write code, you debug them, and changes take a long time.
因为当你写代码的时候  你需要调试它们  而且修改需要花费很长时间
But if you write stuff in paper, you can just erase it and write up new stuff.
但是如果你把东西写在纸上  你就可以直接擦掉它  然后写上新的东西
So here are some example paper prototypes from the game Binding of Isaac.
这里有一些来自游戏《以撒的结合》的纸上原型的例子
I don't think there are any Minecraft paper prototypes lying out there.
我不认为有任何《我的世界》的纸上原型流传在外
So you're going to actually think about one, two, three.
所以你要实际考虑一下  一  二  三
What are the main mechanics?
主要的机制是什么？
And you can change them if you just think those are not good.
如果你觉得那些不好  你可以改变它们
And then after a paper prototype, we'll actually be going into the MVP stage, where we develop a bare bones but still playable version of the game.
在纸上原型之后  我们会进入MVP阶段  在这个阶段  我们会开发一个基本但仍然可以玩的版本的游戏
So the purpose is to tell others that the idea works because it's been implemented into code.
这样做的目的是告诉别人这个想法是可行的  因为它已经被实现成代码了
And this is what the MVP for Minecraft looks like.
这就是《我的世界》的MVP的样子
It's actually the earliest playable version of Minecraft you can see, but it's very bare bones.
这是你能看到的《我的世界》最早的可玩版本  但它非常简陋
There are no other enemies, but there are just like these blocks.
没有其他敌人  只有这些方块
And as a note, given the time we give you on Build Your Own World, your game will likely top up at this stage.
请注意  考虑到我们在“构建你自己的世界”中给你的时间  你的游戏很可能会在这个阶段结束
And then we have Alpha.
然后是 Alpha 版本
So the purpose of Alpha is to show the game to a larger audience, including maybe your friends,
Alpha 版本的目的是向更广泛的受众展示游戏
maybe other people you don't know, and then have them just do a playtest and receive feedback.
比如你的朋友或者你不认识的人  让他们进行游戏测试并收集反馈
So this is Alpha Minecraft, still missing a lot of the real features from the game,
这是 Alpha 版的 Minecraft  它仍然缺少很多正式版的功能
but you see we have trees, we have more advanced things from the base game.
但你能看到我们有树  还有比基础版更高级的东西
And then we have beta, and this will be a preliminary release to the public.
然后是 Beta 版本  这将是面向公众的初步发布版本
So in alpha, your share circle is limited to some people who you know, but if you're doing beta,
在 Alpha 版本中  你的分享范围仅限于你认识的一些人  但如果是 Beta 版本
then you might just post the link online, then people who don't know you would just click on that link and play the game.
你可能会直接将链接发布到网上  那么不认识你的人也可以点击链接并玩游戏
And then you see you have more varied biomes in Minecraft, and you have other fancy stuff.
然后你会看到 Minecraft 中有更多样化的生物群系  还有其他一些很酷的东西
And then for full release, full release is just at some point you decide that you don't want this game to be in beta anymore.
至于正式版  就是指你决定不再让这个游戏处于 Beta 阶段的某个时间点
You just want to announce to the public that this game is an official game.
你想向公众宣布这款游戏是正式版了
And the cutoff can be a little bit blurry.
而这个界限可能有点模糊
You can decide at some point, maybe you want to finalize the game details more, so you just put off.
你可以在某个时候决定  也许你想进一步完善游戏细节  所以你推迟了正式发布
Or you could just do it early and then release version updates.
或者你也可以早点发布  然后发布版本更新
So for Minecraft, this is when you can beat the Ender Dragon and beat the game.
对于 Minecraft 来说  这就是你可以击败末影龙并通关游戏的时候
After the final release, the game is still under active development, and it still receives updates.
在正式版发布后  游戏仍在积极开发中  并且仍然会收到更新
When I started playing Minecraft, it was 1.4.7, but now it's already 1.20-something, and it's still going on.
当我开始玩 Minecraft 时  版本是 1.4.7  但现在已经是 1.20 多了  而且还在继续更新
You can see the game is not a static product.
你可以看到游戏不是一个静态的产品
It's something that you'll build down more and more.
它是你会不断完善的东西
Yeah, and we'll shift gears briefly into programmer perspective.
是的  我们将简要地从程序员的角度来探讨一下
But just before that, if anyone has any questions.
但在那之前  如果有人有任何问题的话
Let's see, do we have any questions?
我们看看  有没有什么问题？
No.
没有
Okay.
Okay, we'll be going on the programming stuff.
好的  我们接下来讲编程方面的内容
So we talked about how games are made in general, like the pipeline things, but we didn't really talk about how we actually code them.
我们之前讨论了游戏制作的总体流程  但没有具体讨论如何编写代码
And this is actually what it's more relevant to like 62MB, because 62MB is like a data structure, of course.
这和 62MB 比较相关  因为 62MB 本身就是一种数据结构
So let's say the problem that we currently have is we want to design a build your own world with encounters, similar to encounter systems in Pokemon.
假设我们现在的目标是设计一个“建造自己的世界”游戏  其中包含类似于《精灵宝可梦》的遭遇系统
So this is the Pokemon world.
这是《精灵宝可梦》的世界
It looks kind of like a build your own world, but What an encounter looks like is this.
它看起来有点像“建造自己的世界”  但是... 遭遇战是这样的
Let's say you're walking randomly and then you trigger, it's kind of like a step on landmine thing.
假设你随机走动  然后触发了遭遇战  有点像踩到地雷一样
You suddenly enter into a battle and then some wild monsters appear and you need to engage and battle with them.
你突然进入战斗  一些野生怪物出现  你需要与它们战斗
So we're going to think about how we can implement this.
所以我们要考虑如何实现这个功能
So if we recall how the basic build run works because we want to build our foundations, you would do this in a while loop.
如果我们回顾一下基本的构建运行原理  因为我们想构建基础  你会在一个 while 循环中进行操作
So process input, update universe, and render the current state to the user.
流程是：处理输入、更新世界状态  然后将当前状态渲染给用户
Now you also want to wait a little bit until the next update because you want the game maybe run at 60 frames per second or something.
你还要等待一段时间直到下一次更新  因为你可能希望游戏以每秒 60 帧的速度运行
Now about keeping the code clean,
关于保持代码整洁
So in our Build Your Own World with Encounters, there are actually different scenes.
在我们的“建造自己的世界”游戏中  实际上有不同的场景
You start at the main menu.
你从主菜单开始
When you press N, you go to the Enter Scene.
当你按下 N 键时  你进入输入场景
And then when you press S, you go to the World Scene.
然后当你按下 S 键时  你进入世界场景
And then at some point, you randomly go into the Encounters Scene.
然后在某个时刻  你会随机进入遭遇战场景
So the problem is that each scene will have different things to update.
问题是每个场景都需要更新不同的东西
So if you're in the world scene, you render blocks and process WSD, but if you're in the encounter scene,
例如  在世界场景中  你需要渲染块并处理WSD  但在遭遇场景中
you don't want to render the world tiles because they're just not in the encounter, but you want to render the information that's pertinent to the encounter.
你不想渲染世界瓦片  因为它们不在遭遇中  而你想渲染与遭遇相关的信息
So let's revisit our requirements given that we've solved those constraints.
既然我们已经解决了这些限制  让我们重新审视一下我们的需求
We want to make the game do different things in different scenes correctly.
我们希望游戏在不同的场景中正确地做不同的事情
And we also want to enable us so that adding new scenes should be relatively easy.
我们也希望能够相对容易地添加新场景
That means you should code in a clean way so that you won't hate your past self.
这意味着你应该用简洁的方式编码  这样你就不会讨厌过去的自己
So how can we do this?
那么我们该如何做到这一点呢？
I'll actually show people two solutions that are attempts but have some shortcomings, and then I'll give a solution that's, to my understanding, pretty clean.
我将向大家展示两种尝试性的解决方案  但都有一些缺点  然后我会提供一个在我看来非常简洁的解决方案
So this is the first thing that we have.
这是我们的第一个方案
We're going to have nested while loops.
我们将使用嵌套的 while 循环
This could be abstracted as their own function.
这可以抽象为它们自己的函数
I could have a title screen that has a while loop.
我可以有一个标题屏幕  它有一个 while 循环
I could have an enter seed that's a while loop.
我可以有一个输入种子的 while 循环
I could have a world movement that's a while loop.
我可以有一个世界移动的 while 循环
But something that we don't like about this if you want to create a new scene,
但我们不喜欢这种方式的一点是如果你想创建一个新场景
you're going to add another nested wild over here.
你就要在这里添加另一个嵌套的 while 循环
This hurts the readability, because the more you indent, the more complicated your code becomes.
这损害了代码的可读性  因为缩进越多  代码就越复杂
Actually, it's not possible to switch back and forth between three scenes using these, because you couldn't just ignore that and then go to the outermost immediately.
实际上  使用这些方法不可能在三个场景之间来回切换  因为你不能简单地忽略它  然后立即跳转到最外层
Now, here's a better approach, but it could still be improved.
现在  这是一个更好的方法  但仍然可以改进
Let's say I have a string variable that represents the current state, and then I just put all these if-else branches to check
假设我有一个字符串变量来表示当前状态  然后我只需将所有这些 if-else 分支放在一起
what is the current scene, and I just do different things accordingly.
以检查当前场景是什么  然后相应地做不同的事情
Now, for people in the chat or maybe this audience, what is something that could be improved about this?
对于聊天室或现场观众来说  有什么地方可以改进的吗？
Or what is something that's not optimal about this code, or not clean?
或者说  这段代码有什么地方不够优化  或者不够简洁？
Yeah, exactly.
是的  没错
You do like a bunch of different equal checks every time, and just to elaborate a little bit on that, let's say you want to add a new scene.
每次你都要做一堆不同的相等检查  为了更详细地说明这一点  假设你想添加一个新的场景
What would you do?
你会怎么做？
What would you need to do here?
你需要在这里做什么？
Yeah, you need to add another statement, and that's something we kind of don't want
是的  你需要添加另一个语句  而这是我们不希望看到的
because your game is just going to have if, else, if, else, if repeated a hundred times, and that just doesn't look very clean.
因为你的游戏将会有 if、else、if、else、if 重复上百次  这看起来很不简洁
This is the best we can think of at the moment, but how do we actually tackle this problem?
这是我们目前能想到的最好的办法  但是我们如何真正解决这个问题呢？
I'm going to first introduce a conceptual tool, and then we're going to see how we can use this conceptual tool to tackle the previous problem of handling different scenes.
我首先要介绍一个概念工具  然后我们将看看如何使用这个概念工具来解决之前处理不同场景的问题
This concept is called a finite state machine, and it's used to manage complex games with a lot of different scenes.
这个概念叫做有限状态机  它用于管理具有许多不同场景的复杂游戏
Specifically for Flappy Bird,If you recall how the Flappy Bird works,
特别是在 Flappy Bird 中  如果你还记得 Flappy Bird 的工作原理
you're going to start with title screen, and then you're going to go to countdown, and you have three, two, one, go.
你会从标题画面开始  然后进入倒计时  你有 3、2、1  开始
And then you go to the play state.
然后你进入游戏状态
And then once your game is over, you go to the score state.
一旦游戏结束  你就会进入得分状态
And then after you're done with the score state, you go to a countdown state again if you want to play again, you know.
在你完成得分状态之后  如果你想再次玩游戏  你会再次进入倒计时状态
And then you just go back.
然后你就回去了
Now, what sort of data structure does this remind you of that we've covered in this class?
现在  这让你想起了我们在本课程中讲过的哪种数据结构？
I heard someone say graphs, and that's entirely correct.
我听到有人说图  这完全正确
This is a directed graph.
这是一个有向图
So it is a lot like it.
所以它很像
The vertices are just the states that the machine could be in.
这些顶点表示机器可能处于的状态
You know, you have the title and recede, and then the edges are just the transitions from one state to another.
你知道  你有标题和后退状态  然后边表示从一个状态到另一个状态的转换
So one example, if you're in the title and you push L, you should be able to load directly into the world.
举个例子  如果你在标题状态下按 L 键  你应该能够直接加载到世界场景中
And then the machine can only be in one state at a time.
机器在同一时间只能处于一种状态
So you'll need a variable to keep track of that.
所以你需要一个变量来跟踪它
And that makes it different from a directed graph because the directed graph doesn't have a current state.
这使得它与有向图不同  因为有向图没有当前状态的概念
Now we're going to have a sequence of inputs slash events that are sent to the machine.
现在我们将有一系列输入/事件发送到机器
And then you can check if any outgoing edges from your current state have their transition conditions fulfilled.
然后你可以检查当前状态的任何出边是否满足其转换条件
Now that sounds like a mouthful, but I'll kind of like give some examples and clean code like next slides.
这听起来可能有点复杂  但我稍后会通过一些例子和代码来解释
So we talked about general walkthrough of the finite state machine.
我们已经讨论了有限状态机的概述
Let's now take a look at how the build-driven world with encounters could be modeled by.
现在让我们看看如何用它来模拟构建驱动的世界和遭遇战
So you have the title Enter Seed World.
所以你有标题  输入种子  世界
So we have the N go to Enter Seed and S go to World.
我们有 N 转到输入种子  S 转到世界
You also have the L directly loads into the world.
你也可以直接用 L 加载到世界
And you have the exit game.
还有退出游戏
And let's say the user steps on a coin door and that brings them to a world full of coins.
假设用户踏上一个硬币门  这将带他们进入一个充满硬币的世界
And then that's just an encounter.
那只是一个遭遇战
So that's another edge and that's another scene.
所以这是另一个边  也是另一个场景
And then when the user collects all the coins, they're going to go to a game win scene.
当用户收集所有硬币后  他们将进入游戏胜利场景
And then if the timer runs out, they're just going to go to a game over scene.
如果计时器结束  他们将进入游戏结束场景
So you're going to have a restart.
所以  你需要重启
If you are in those states and you press maybe R for restart or something,
如果你处于这些状态  你可能按下R键来重启
So here's how you could potentially implement a finite state machine in code.
那么  这里是如何在代码中实现有限状态机
So you're going to have something that represents your current state machine.
所以  你要有一个东西来表示你当前的状态机
And then you're going to have your main game loop.
然后  你要有你的主游戏循环
So you read the input, you do some updates based on the input, and then you render to the user.
你读取输入  根据输入做一些更新  然后渲染给用户
Now, how will the state machine class look like?
现在  状态机类会是什么样子？
Well, the state machine class is going to look like this hash map with a map from the different states to the actual game state object.
状态机类看起来像一个哈希映射  将不同的状态映射到实际的游戏状态对象
So you're going to initialize all the individual game states, and then you're going to have a current state.
所以你要初始化所有单独的游戏状态  然后你还要有一个当前状态
Now, the state machine is going to have an update method, which basically gets the current state and then calls the update of that state.
现在  状态机将有一个更新方法  它基本上获取当前状态  然后调用该状态的更新
And then there's just only one line there.
然后那里只有一行代码
And then the render is just going to call the render of that state.
然后渲染只会调用该状态的渲染
So it's pretty bare bones.
所以它很精简
It doesn't have anything.
它什么都没有
The actual stuff that's being implemented is the individual update and render methods.
实际实现的东西是单独的更新和渲染方法
So if you have change state, well, change state needs two things.
如果你改变状态  那么改变状态需要两件事
You need to execute the exit function and the enter function of the target state.
你需要执行目标状态的退出函数和进入函数
And then I'm just going to define an interface of game state that has all the pressed, render, enter, exit.
然后  我将定义一个游戏状态的接口  它具有所有的按键、渲染、进入、退出
So now, if I want to add new game states, I could just implement that game state interface.
现在  如果我想添加新的游戏状态  我只需要实现那个游戏状态接口
Yeah, this was from last slides.
是的  这是上一张幻灯片的内容
If you have the world state, the update function could be like, you know, move your avatar based on the pressed.
如果有了世界状态  更新函数可以像这样  根据按键移动你的角色
And then if you step on the door, you're gonna call machine.changeState into the encounter.
然后  如果你踩到门上  你就会调用 mach.changeState("encounter")进入遭遇战
And then the render is just gonna draw the world.
然后渲染器就会绘制世界
Now, public class encounter state, this is another game state.
现在  public class 遭遇状态  这是另一个游戏状态
You're gonna take in the pressed,
你会接受按键输入
Now you're going to maybe move your avatar based on press, depending on what you want to do in your encounter.
现在你可能会根据按键移动你的角色  这取决于你想在遭遇战中做什么
If the encounter has to do with characters moving around, then that could be possible.
如果遭遇战与角色的移动有关  那么这是可能的
Now if you want the encounter, you're going to call another change state, and you're going to maybe go back to the world, or you can just go to the win stage.
现在  如果你想要结束遭遇战  你将调用另一个 mach.changeState  你可能会回到世界  或者你可以直接进入胜利阶段
Yeah, and then there's another render method.
是的  然后还有另一个渲染方法
Now, how does the game exactly know which update and render to call?
那么  游戏究竟是如何知道要调用哪个更新和渲染的呢？
Remember in Java, we have this method overwriting,
记住在Java中  我们有这种方法重写
Where we actually see that the overridden method is run, if we call that update method from there.
在那里我们实际上看到重写的方法被运行  如果我们从那里调用更新方法
You have different states based on how you instantiate them, so Java is gonna know by overwriting to pick which one is the correct to run.
你根据实例化它们的方式拥有不同的状态  所以Java会通过重写来知道选择哪个是正确的运行
Yeah.
Okay, so before we talk about game engines, any questions here?
好的  在我们谈论游戏引擎之前  这里有任何问题吗？
Someone in the back?
后面的有人吗？
The question is, can we use state machines for the actual project in Project 3?
问题是  我们可以在项目3的实际项目中使用状态机吗？
And the answer is yes, because the general structure is a really cool concept.
答案是肯定的  因为总体结构是一个非常酷的概念
The actual implementation details are up to you, but the design idea is going to make the stuff much cleaner.
实际的实现细节取决于你  但是设计思路会让事情变得更清晰
Actually, I would be kind of pleased if someone decides to use a state machine to do all the scenes.
实际上  如果有人决定使用状态机来完成所有场景  我会感到非常高兴
If there are no more questions, let's do a time check.
如果没有其他问题了  我们来确认一下时间
Then let's move on to the game engine part.
然后我们进入游戏引擎的部分
Now, based on the discussion from Java, like you've seen before, coding games from scratch is really hard because it requires code that exists in most games.
基于之前Java的讨论  你们也看到了  从头开始编写游戏代码真的很困难  因为它需要在大多数游戏中都存在的代码
Like the scene transition thing, you're probably gonna think about like, okay, because you have so many different games that have scene transition, you're probably gonna have all the repeated code.
就像场景转换的东西  你可能会想  好吧  因为你有很多不同的游戏都有场景转换  你可能会重复所有的代码
Can we just somehow abstract away all those redundant code, also called boilerplate?
我们能不能以某种方式抽象出所有这些冗余的代码  也称为样板代码？
And the answer is game engines.
答案就是游戏引擎
So one example is called Unity.
举个例子  叫做Unity
Unity is abstracted so well that you could develop games codelessly.
Unity被抽象得很好  你可以不用写代码就开发游戏
In Unity, everything that exists in a game is called a GameObject.
在Unity中  游戏中存在的所有东西都称为GameObject（游戏对象）
You can download GameObjects made by others, and you can drag and drop the objects in the Unity editor.
你可以下载别人制作的GameObjects  并将其拖放到Unity编辑器中
This is an example of a LEGO blocks world.
这是一个乐高积木世界的例子
What's cool about this LEGO block is that when you attach this blue block to the platform, it will enable the platform to move up and down periodically.
这个乐高积木的酷炫之处在于  当你将这个蓝色积木连接到平台上时  它将使平台能够周期性地上下移动
So you don't have to write any code because the code that does this is already written for you.
所以你不需要编写任何代码  因为执行此操作的代码已经为你写好了
Now, even if you decide to write some sort of a code, the engine still abstracts a lot away from you.
现在  即使你决定编写某种代码  引擎仍然会为你抽象出很多东西
In Build Your Own World, you need to come up with class definitions for Java classes, but in Unity, you can just define what are the sort of game objects that you want,
在“构建你自己的世界”中  你需要为Java类提出类定义  但在Unity中  你只需定义你想要的什么样的游戏对象
and you can attach something called a script component to the game object you want to control.
然后将一个名为脚本组件的东西附加到你想要控制的游戏对象
There are some rules for this script, and specifically it should inherit the MonoBehaviour and then override these two functions.
这个脚本有一些规则  特别是它应该继承MonoBehaviour  然后重写这两个函数
You should define what the object should do when it's been initialized, and you should define what it should do at every frame.
你应该定义对象在初始化时应该做什么  以及它在每一帧应该做什么
And then you're just going to call those methods behind the scenes for you.
然后你只需要在幕后调用这些方法
Now you might wonder, okay, what about scene transition?
现在你可能想知道  好吧  那场景转换呢？
We talked about scene transition like maybe a few minutes before.
我们几分钟前讨论过场景转换
How does Unity handle that?
Unity 是如何处理场景转换的？
Well, Unity has a finite state machine that's running behind the scenes, and they actually provide you functions that you can use to change those things.
Unity 后台运行着一个有限状态机  它提供了一些函数来改变场景状态
In the Unity editor, you can click on the File, New Scene to create a new scene for your game.
在 Unity 编辑器中  你可以点击“文件”  “新建场景”来为你的游戏创建一个新场景
You can define what the game objects need to exist in that scene, and you can actually tell them, okay, here's what you should do when the scene starts.
你可以定义场景中需要存在哪些游戏对象  并告诉它们在场景开始时应该做什么
Maybe if this is your player, initialize the health to 100, set the score to zero or something.
例如  如果这是你的玩家  可以将生命值初始化为 100  将分数设置为零等等
And then when you want to transition between the scenes, you just call this function called sceneManager.loadScene.
然后  当你想要在场景之间转换时  只需调用 sceneManager.loadScene 函数即可
Now here's an example of a scene.
这是一个场景示例
Here's another scene.
这是另一个场景
Here's a lose scene.
这是一个失败场景
And this is the code I've written for these two parts.
这是我为这两个部分编写的代码
I actually opened up this Unity editor.
我打开了 Unity 编辑器
So this is the camera object.
这是摄像机对象
It has all the other stuff.
它包含了所有其他内容
You can see that there's a script that does the camera movement stuff.
你可以看到有一个脚本负责摄像机的移动
How do you make the camera follow the player?
如何让摄像机跟随玩家？
And then this is your player.
这是你的玩家
These are just for the physics of the player, but then you also have a player controller script.
这些是玩家的物理属性  还有一个玩家控制器脚本
And then you can just define what scenes you have here.
你可以在这里定义场景
And here is just the very bare bones like lose scene.
这是一个非常简单的失败场景
You're going to define that you have like some sort of like a canvas to draw on and then you just say like you lose there.
你需要定义一个画布  然后在上面显示“游戏失败”之类的信息
Yeah, I can even like you know drag this player around to change his starting position and it's going to start a little bit off-centered, but that's it.
嗯  我甚至可以拖动这个角色来改变他的起始位置  它会稍微偏离中心一点  就是这样
There's still some general tips about writing good code.
关于编写好的代码还有一些通用技巧
For example, don't repeat yourself.
例如  不要重复你自己
You shouldn't try to make different variants of an enemy, but you should just try to make one and inherit from that.
你不应该尝试制作敌人的不同变体  而应该尝试制作一个并从中继承
If you have different versions of slimes, for example, you can just make three subclasses that all inherit from one superclass.
例如  如果你有不同版本的史莱姆  你可以只创建三个子类  它们都继承自一个超类
You should also try to separate data from logic if you want to write games that are relatively big.
如果你想编写相对较大的游戏  你也应该尝试将数据与逻辑分离
You maybe want to store them in a text file or somewhere else.
你可能想将它们存储在文本文件或其他地方
Just don't hard-code in the game because you're going to have a really long page of code that just has all the constants.
不要在游戏中硬编码  因为你将会有一个很长的代码页面  其中包含所有常量
I think it might make your code a little bit bloated.
我认为这可能会使你的代码有点臃肿
Also, you should learn to work with different types of assets, which are resources used in games, so like images, audio, or 3D models.
此外  你还应该学习使用不同类型的资产  这些资产是游戏中使用的资源  比如图像、音频或 3D 模型
You also need to know some algorithms.
你还需要了解一些算法
For example, A-Star pathfinding is actually used by zombies in Minecraft.
例如  《我的世界》中的僵尸实际上使用了 A* 寻路算法
As a matter of fact, I think Project 3C has one feature that you can do, which is to implement some sort of pathfinding for enemies to chase, like the Avatar. Something similar to that.
事实上  我认为 Project 3C 有一个功能可以实现  那就是为敌人实现某种寻路算法来追逐  比如化身等类似的东西
Finally, don't repeat yourself.
最后  不要重复你自己
We're not going to talk about game modding.
我们不打算谈论游戏模组
It's another shift of gears.
这是另一个话题
Let's say you don't want a dirty work of creating all like a brand new game.
假设你不想做创建全新游戏的脏活累活
But then let's say I really love one of those existing games.
但是假设我真的很喜欢其中一个现有的游戏
I want to just modify the things that are going on it.
我只想修改它上面发生的事情
And this is actually called game modding.
这实际上叫做游戏模组（game modding）
It modifies the existing gameplay experience or just like adds new content to it.
它可以修改现有的游戏体验  或者像这样添加新的内容
So one way is to add new levels.
所以一种方法是添加新的关卡
This is a music game called OCE, where you just click on those circles and then those slide bars in time.
这是一个叫做 OCE 的音乐游戏  你只需要点击那些圆圈  然后及时地点击那些滑动条
But then the game actually gives you a tool to add new beats according to a song that you like.
但然后游戏实际上给了你一个工具  可以根据你喜欢的歌曲添加新的节拍
Now Super Mario games also have player-made level editors that you can drag and drop all the pipes, enemies, and stuff.
现在超级马里奥游戏也有玩家自制的关卡编辑器  你可以拖放所有的管道、敌人和其他东西
Now you can also choose to add new content using code, and I'm going to show the Terraria code here.
现在你也可以选择使用代码添加新的内容  我将在这里展示泰拉瑞亚（Terraria）的代码
This is the mod I try to do.
这是我尝试做的模组
So we're going to try to create a sword called the Sword of 61B in Terraria, and it's going to deal 61 damage,
所以我们要尝试在泰拉瑞亚中创建一个叫做 61B 之剑的剑  它将造成 61 点伤害
now less than 61 because enemy has some defense, and it's going to show this flavor text whenever you hit an enemy.
所以现在小于 61 点是因为敌人有一些防御  并且每当你击中敌人时  它将显示这段文字
So how do I do this?
那么我该如何做呢？
Well, I'm just gonna write a code that's like, you know, a sort 61B that extends like some sort of a class.
我只需要写一个代码  就像一个排序 61B 的类  它扩展了某种类型的类
Now you might wonder, okay, how do I know it's these classes?
现在你可能会想  好吧  我怎么知道是这些类呢？
How do I know it's not something else?
我怎么知道它不是其他的东西呢？
And the answer to that is like, you should read the documentation you found online, and that should tell you like what you should do.
答案是  你应该阅读你在网上找到的文档  它应该会告诉你应该做什么
Now, we've talked about hacking into games, kind of, coding and stuff, or adding new levels.
现在  我们已经讨论过破解游戏  有点像  编码之类的东西  或者添加新的关卡
So some of you might actually wonder, is this a legal thing to do?
你们中的一些人可能真的想知道  这样做合法吗？
So in the actual beginning, most games don't have modding support.
在实际开始的时候  大多数游戏都没有模组支持
So it's actually not that legit.
它实际上并不那么合法
But then, some people in the community really want to change stuff in the game.
但是  社区里的一些人真的想改变游戏中的东西
They got bored playing the base game.
他们玩基础游戏玩腻了
So they eventually reverse engineered the games.
他们最终对游戏进行了逆向工程
And then they created support for those mod support platforms.
然后他们为这些模组支持平台创建了支持
And then some game companies realized that the game modding actually helps the original game.
然后一些游戏公司意识到游戏模组实际上有助于原始游戏
We talked about this at the beginning of the lecture.
我们在课程开始时讨论过这个
If the player does a successful run, they just get bored.
如果玩家成功运行  他们就会感到无聊
And specifically the reason I still play Minecraft is because of mods.
我仍然玩《我的世界》的具体原因就是因为模组
I wouldn't play vanilla Minecraft runs because I've done them so many times.
我不会玩原版《我的世界》的运行  因为我已经玩过很多次了
So eventually modding just became semi-officially supported.
所以最终模组就变成了半官方支持的
And these are just some of the bottom lines you should be aware of.
这些只是你应该注意的一些底线
Don't mod a game if the developer bans it and don't mod a game.
如果开发者禁止模组游戏  就不要模组游戏  也不要模组游戏
When you're modding the game, don't release the source code.
当你模组游戏时  不要发布源代码
And for some games, the game companies just decided to release an official modding support tool at the very start.
对于某些游戏  游戏公司决定从一开始就发布官方模组支持工具
Some example games of these.
其中一些游戏的例子
Now, As I mentioned before, the game companies and the game modders have some interesting dynamics
现在  正如我之前提到的  游戏公司和游戏模组制作者之间有一些有趣的动态
because game developers are going to take away from good mods and add them to the game.
因为游戏开发者会从好的模组中吸取经验  并将它们添加到游戏中
As you can see, this game called Binding of Isaac released its patch and on the features it says the fan mod
正如你所看到的  这款名为《以撒的结合》的游戏发布了它的补丁  在功能上写着风扇模式
The Binding of Isaac and Type Earth integrate into game as official content.
《以撒的结合》和《地球类型》作为官方内容整合到游戏中
So you can see those game developers really taking away from the community it did for them.
你可以看到那些游戏开发者真的从社区为他们所做的事情中吸取了经验
Taking the good and then maybe leaving the not so good part.
取其精华  去其糟粕
So this is really like a two-sided relationship where you give something, you learn something.
这真的像一种双向的关系  你付出一些东西  你学到一些东西
Yeah. Now another example is Super Mario Maker.
另一个例子是《超级马里奥制造》
So now we have a lot of players creating their own levels.
现在我们有很多玩家都在创建自己的关卡
So why don't we just create a game that's about making new levels?
那么为什么我们不直接创造一个关于制作新关卡的游戏呢？
So that's Super Mario Maker.
那就是《超级马里奥制造》
All right, so we're almost at the end of today's lecture, but as a summary of today's lecture content, we covered coming up with good game ideas,
好的  今天的课程快结束了  总结一下今天的内容  我们讲了如何想出好的游戏点子
we covered the pipelines for making a game, so like a, kind of like a, this is six-stage, yeah, six-stage pipeline, and we covered writing code for games,
我们讲了制作游戏的流程  有点像一个六阶段的流程  我们讲了为游戏编写代码
we talked about coding games in Java and talked about Unity, and we also talked briefly about modding an existing game.
我们讨论了用Java编写游戏  还讨论了Unity  我们还简要地谈到了修改现有的游戏
So if you take a look at all these layers, at each layer, you're going to lose some of the freedom, but you're going to do less dirty work.
所以  如果你看一下所有这些层  在每一层  你都会失去一些自由  但你会减少一些脏活累活
If you're modding, you don't have to start anything from scratch.
如果你在做模组  你就不必从头开始做任何事情
But the good thing about indie game development is that you can choose which layer you enjoy the most when you develop the game, because you're not constrained by deadlines or the company goals.
但独立游戏开发的好处是  你可以在开发游戏时选择你最喜欢的层  因为你不会受到截止日期或公司目标的限制
So you can just do whatever you want.
你可以做任何你想做的事
So therefore, I just hope you enjoyed this lecture.
因此  我希望你喜欢这节课
I hope you find this very helpful, and you would consider developing this as a hobby.
希望你觉得这很有帮助  你会考虑把这作为一种爱好来发展
Yeah, thank you, everyone.
好的  谢谢大家
I'm now moving to questions.
我现在开始提问
Yeah, any questions?
好  有什么问题吗？
Yeah.
Do you have any idea of how the Twitter application cycle
你知道Twitter的应用程序周期吗
Okay, so the question is, do I have any idea about the recruitment cycles or recruiting for game companies?
所以问题是  我对游戏公司的招聘周期或招聘有什么想法吗？
I'm sorry, but I do not have that knowledge about this because I'm just an indie game developer.
对不起  我对此不太了解  因为我只是一个独立游戏开发者
I do not work for a game company.
我不在游戏公司工作
So yeah, I do not have that knowledge.
嗯  我没有这方面的知识
Yeah.
Yeah, so the question is, you know, what is the life of an indie game developer look like?
那么问题是  独立游戏开发者的生活是什么样的？
So honestly, this is something that I do like as a hobby.
老实说  我把它当作一种爱好
This is actually something I thought about, you know, what's it like if you do things indie or on your side?
我确实想过  如果做独立的事情或副业会是什么样子？
It's kind of like running a startup or like, you know, starting like a, I don't know, like a sidekick.
这有点像经营一家初创公司  或者  你知道  开始像一个  我不知道  像一个副业
The key idea is that You're going to be responsible for your own work.
关键是你要对自己的工作负责
It could be demanding, it could be not.
它可能要求很高  也可能不需要
You can always pace yourself.
你可以随时调整自己的节奏
Honestly, this semester I probably wouldn't have that much time for game development because my coursework is really tight and I have grad school applications and stuff.
老实说  这学期我可能没有太多时间进行游戏开发  因为我的课程真的很紧  而且我还有研究生院的申请等等
So the thing about this is that you should pace yourself and then it's your own work.
这件事的关键是你要调整自己的节奏  然后这是你自己的工作
If you do well, it's your own thing, but then nobody else is going to take credit for that.
如果你做得好  那是你自己的事  但没有人会因此而获得荣誉
So you need to be fully responsible for all of your things.
你需要对你的所有事情负全部责任
That's what I'm going to be saying.
这就是我要说的
It really depends on you.
这真的取决于你
Q&A here.
问答环节
Terraria weapon mod was that simple?
泰拉瑞亚武器模组就这么简单吗？
I'm going to answer this question live.
我将现场回答这个问题
This is actually kind of simplified, but Terraria weapon mod uses this tool called tmodloader.
这实际上是简化了  但泰拉瑞亚武器模组使用了一个名为 tmodloader 的工具
They actually have this tutorial which you can read about.
他们实际上有一个教程  你可以阅读它
But they did provide really good abstractions where you can define all these attributes and then do that.
但是他们确实提供了非常好的抽象  你可以在其中定义所有这些属性  然后执行操作
I'm actually not going to link it, but you can search tmodloader on GitHub and they'd have a pretty good Wikipedia page you can read about.
我实际上不会链接它  但是你可以在 GitHub 上搜索 tmodloader  他们有一个相当不错的维基百科页面供你阅读
Yeah, but then tmodloader makes making mods in Terrara really, really simple.
是的  但是 tmodloader 使得在泰拉瑞亚中制作模组变得非常非常简单
Any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
Yeah.
So the question is, after you made a game, which platform would you use to publish it?
所以问题是  在你制作游戏之后  你会使用哪个平台发布它？
And then my first answer to this is something that starts with S, and that's Steam.
然后我的第一个答案是以 S 开头的东西  那就是 Steam
So Steam is my first go-to if it were to publish games.
如果要发布游戏  Steam 是我的首选
I think the good thing is Players can, you know, so first of all like if you want your game to be somewhat monetized, like Steam has like some support for that.
我认为好处是玩家可以(挣钱)  你知道  如果你想让你的游戏在某种程度上货币化  就像 Steam 一样  它有一些支持
But also, you know, you can have something called like a, I don't know what's that called, it's called a workshop or something,
而且  你可以拥有一个叫做  我不知道那叫什么  它叫做工作室之类的东西
but you can actually support players to make mods through your own game by having a Steam workshop.
但是你实际上可以通过拥有 Steam 工作室来支持玩家通过你自己的游戏制作模组
Another good platform is called itch.io, which I actually kind of showed here.
另一个好的平台叫做 itch.io  我实际上在这里展示了一下
If I click on this, it brings me to itch.
如果我点击这个  它会带我到 itch
And then itch is a place where indie game developers can put their own games on there.
然后 itch 是一个独立游戏开发者可以放置他们自己的游戏的地方
Yeah.
I played on TMOT Loader for 80 hours already, never even read that.
我已经在 TMOT Loader 上玩了 80 个小时了  甚至从来没有读过那个
I think it's gonna happen because they're just two different roles they're playing.
我认为这会发生  因为他们只是扮演了两个不同的角色
Tmod loader has this page where like, okay, if I'm a player, read this.
Tmod loader 有这样一个页面  上面写着  如果我是一个玩家  就读这个
If you're a player, read this.
如果你是玩家  请阅读本文
If you're a developer, read this.
如果你是开发者  请看这里
So I think that's totally fine.
我觉得这完全没问题
Maybe Tmodding sometimes just feels a little bit too much work for people.
可能对某些人来说  Tmodding 有点费劲
But yeah, I'm actually gonna open up the Tmod loader GitHub page.
但我实际上要打开 Tmod loader 的 GitHub 页面
Yeah, maybe if you're interested, you can take a look at that.
如果你有兴趣  可以看看
So yeah, if I click on I'm a Player, it's just going to tell you how to install tmodloader.
如果我点击“我是玩家”  它会告诉你如何安装 tmodloader
But you know, if you don't just want to play, there's a bunch of tutorials, and I think it's pretty well written.
如果你不仅仅想玩游戏  这里有很多教程  而且我觉得写得很好
Yeah, there are these guys over there.
那边有几个人
Alright, I think that's all the time we have.
好的  我想这就是我们所有的時間了